export default {
  id: 'mid_3b',
  name: '상용한자(중학3/한자찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '독:あ(げる)、あ(がる)/음:よう', answer: ['揚'] },
    { question: '독:종기, 상처/음:よう', answer: ['瘍'] },
    { question: '독:항상/음:こう', answer: ['恒'] },
    { question: '독:かき/음:', answer: ['垣'] },
    { question: '독:맏, 우두머리/음:はく', answer: ['伯'] },
    { question: '독:칠/음:はく、[ひょう]', answer: ['拍'] },
    { question: '독:と(まる)、と(める)/음:はく', answer: ['泊'] },
    { question: '독:큰 배/음:はく', answer: ['舶'] },
    { question: '독:せま(る)/음:はく', answer: ['迫'] },
    { question: '독:샘/음:せん', answer: ['腺'] },
    { question: '독:たな/음:', answer: ['棚'] },
    { question: '독:くず(れる)、くず(す)/음:ほう', answer: ['崩'] },
    { question: '독:へび/음:じゃ、だ', answer: ['蛇'] },
    { question: '독:まゆ/음:けん', answer: ['繭'] },
    { question: '독:むね/음:し', answer: ['旨'] },
    { question: '독:うぶら/음:し', answer: ['脂'] },
    { question: '독:もう(でる)/음:けい', answer: ['詣'] },
    { question: '독:しず(める)、しず(まる)/음:ちん', answer: ['鎮'] },
    { question: '독:채울/음:てん', answer: ['填'] },
    { question: '독:つつし(む)/음:しん', answer: ['慎'] },
    { question: '독:마칠/음:ひ', answer: ['罷'] },
    { question: '독:くま/음:', answer: ['熊'] },
    { question: '독:맏, 벌레/음:こん', answer: ['昆'] },
    { question: '독:みな/음:かい', answer: ['皆'] },
    { question: '독:어울릴/음:かい', answer: ['諧'] },
    { question: '독:본보기/음:かい', answer: ['楷'] },
    { question: '독:しか、[か]/음:', answer: ['鹿'] },
    { question: '독:ふもと/음:ろく', answer: ['麓'] },
    { question: '독:うるわ(しい)/음:れい', answer: ['麗'] },
    { question: '독:경사/음:けい', answer: ['慶'] },
    { question: '독:すす(める)/음:せん', answer: ['薦'] },
    { question: '독:くつ/음:か', answer: ['靴'] },
    { question: '독:으뜸/음:は', answer: ['覇'] },
    { question: '독:고리/음:かん', answer: ['環'] },
    { question: '독:돌아올/음:かん', answer: ['還'] },
    { question: '독:임신/음:しん', answer: ['娠'] },
    { question: '독:ふ(る)、ふ(るう)、ふ(れる)/음:しん', answer: ['振'] },
    { question: '독:くちびる/음:しん', answer: ['唇'] },
    { question: '독:ふる(う)、ふる(える)/음:しん', answer: ['震'] },
    { question: '독:はずかし(める)/음:じょく', answer: ['辱'] },
    { question: '독:こい/음:のう', answer: ['濃'] },
    { question: '독:무리/음:そう', answer: ['曹'] },
    { question: '독:통/음:そう', answer: ['槽'] },
    { question: '독:あ(う)/음:そう', answer: ['遭'] },
    { question: '독:つや/음:えん', answer: ['艶'] },
    { question: '독:かる/음:', answer: ['刈'] },
    { question: '독:짧은시간, 절/음:さつ、せつ', answer: ['刹'] },
    { question: '독:흉할/음:きょう', answer: ['凶'] },
    { question: '독:さわ(やか)/음:そう', answer: ['爽'] },
    { question: '독:옥새, 도장/음:じ', answer: ['璽'] },
    { question: '독:유리/음:り', answer: ['璃'] },
    { question: '독:はな(れる)、はな(す)/음:り', answer: ['離'] },
    { question: '독:し(ぼる)、し(める)、し(まる)/음:こう', answer: ['絞'] },
    { question: '독:かく/음:', answer: ['較'] },
    { question: '독:교외/음:こう', answer: ['郊'] },
    { question: '독:くだ(く)、くだ(ける)/음:さい', answer: ['砕'] },
    { question: '독:いき/음:すい', answer: ['粋'] },
    { question: '독:よう/음:すい', answer: ['酔'] },
    { question: '독:か/음:', answer: ['蚊'] },
    { question: '독:무늬/음:もん', answer: ['紋'] },
    { question: '독:얼룩/음:はん', answer: ['斑'] },
    { question: '독:의지할/음:い、[え]', answer: ['依'] },
    { question: '독:も/음:そう', answer: ['喪'] },
    { question: '독:あわ(れ)、あわ(れむ)/음:あい', answer: ['哀'] },
    { question: '독:おとろ(える)/음:すい', answer: ['衰'] },
    { question: '독:속마음/음:ちゅう', answer: ['衷'] },
    { question: '독:さる/음:えん', answer: ['猿'] },
    { question: '독:ほ(める)/음:ほう', answer: ['褒'] },
    { question: '독:수건/음:きん', answer: ['巾'] },
    { question: '독:にしき/음:きん', answer: ['錦'] },
    { question: '독:장수/음:すい', answer: ['帥'] },
    { question: '독:かき/음:', answer: ['柿'] },
    { question: '독:とどこお(る)/음:たい', answer: ['滞'] },
    { question: '독:こわ(い)/음:ふ', answer: ['怖'] },
    { question: '독:かざ(る)/음:しょく', answer: ['飾'] },
    { question: '독:동료/음:りょう', answer: ['僚'] },
    { question: '독:밝을/음:りょう', answer: ['瞭'] },
    { question: '독:집, 동료/음:りょう', answer: ['寮'] },
    { question: '독:병고칠/음:りょう', answer: ['療'] },
    { question: '독:まゆ/음:び、[み]', answer: ['眉'] },
    { question: '독:장님/음:もう', answer: ['盲'] },
    { question: '독:ねむ(る)、ねむ(い)/음:みん', answer: ['眠'] },
    { question: '독:うらむ、うらめしい/음:こん', answer: ['恨'] },
    { question: '독:あと/음:こん', answer: ['痕'] },
    { question: '독:むすめ/음:', answer: ['娘'] },
    { question: '독:물결/음:ろう', answer: ['浪'] },
    { question: '독:사내/음:ろう', answer: ['郎'] },
    { question: '독:행랑/음:ろう', answer: ['廊'] },
    { question: '독:너그러울/음:かん', answer: ['寛'] },
    { question: '독:えさ、え/음:じ', answer: ['餌'] },
    { question: '독:は(じる)、は(じ)、は(じらう)、は(ずかしい)/음:ち', answer: ['恥'] },
    { question: '독:끌어당길, 알맞게할/음:せつ', answer: ['摂'] },
    { question: '독:おもむき/음:しゅ', answer: ['趣'] },
    { question: '독:と(る)/음:さつ', answer: ['撮'] },
    { question: '독:うれ(え)る、うれ(い)、う(い)/음:ゆう', answer: ['憂'] },
    { question: '독:くさ(い)、にお(う)/음:しゅう', answer: ['臭'] },
    { question: '독:か(ぐ)/음:きゅう', answer: ['嗅'] },
    { question: '독:おか(す)/음:ぼう', answer: ['冒'] },
    { question: '독:모자/음:ぼう', answer: ['帽'] }
  ]
}
